Scott Schroeder

snschroeder89@gmail.com (281) 796-9760

Full Stack Developer

GitHub LinkedIn

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer experienced in Javascript/Typescript, React, Node.js, and PostgreSQL. I follow a test-driven approach to develop intuitive and friendly UI/UXs that integrate with robust and secure back ends. I enjoy collaborating with other developers, solving novel problems, and learning new technologies.

Technical Skills

Front end: Javascript, Typescript, React, Jest/Enzyme, HTML5/CSS3 *Back end:* Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, MongoDB, Python, Flask

Other: Python, Shopify, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3), Docker, Git, JWT, Chart.js, Wordpress, Ubuntu

Experience

PS Audio

Web Developer July 2020 – Sep 2023

- Worked in an agile environment to efficiently evaluate and react to changes.
- Led meetings with stakeholders to identify and adjust project requirements.
- Created project documentation based on these requirements to establish deadlines and milestones.
- Built or extended applications to meet the needs defined in the documentation.
- Tested and deployed applications either privately on company intranet or publicly on AWS.
- Provided continuous support and updates based on user and stakeholder feedback.
- Identified and learned new technologies to best meet the needs of company projects.
- Designed responsive front-ends to mirror mockups or wireframes.
- Major projects:
 - Built and maintained full stack diagnostic and reporting applications for in-field products.
 - Built and maintained a full stack burn-in and testing application to certify products prior to sale.

Domestic Sales Manager

Oct 2014 - May 2019

- Solely managed all US dealers, growing revenue and profit year-over-year throughout my tenure.
- Acted as liaison between sales and developers by managing content updates, edits, and minor bug fixes on our eCommerce platform.
- Created and distributed marketing content on the company website, forum, and through email campaigns.
- Official company drone pilot/videographer.

THINKFUL Aug 2019 – Jan 2020

Full Stack Developer Apprentice

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Javascript, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first apps while learning new frameworks.
- Weekly collaborations with a senior web developer to deepen my understanding of coding concepts and best practices.

Education

The University of Oklahoma

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism - Minor in Japanese

Aug 2009 - May 2013

Additional code samples available upon request